Present Address: -

Indirapuram, Ghaziabad, (UP) India Contact No. 9971972388 Email id: durgeshdayal6@gmail.com

Mrs. Durgesh

SEO Specialist | Digital Marketing | Link Building Specialist

Professional Summary

Highly skilled, detailed-oriented marketing professional with 5 years of experience in SEO, Link Building & Digital Marketing. I am proficient in using a variety of SEO tools & techniques. Also aware of digital marketing tactics, including content marketing, social media marketing, and email marketing.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Off-Page/On-Page SEO
- Link Building
- Content Optimization
- Keyword Research
- Google & Facebook Ads
- Technical SEO
- Tools- Ahrefs, SEMrush, Moz, Google Analytics, GSC, Google Trends

Soft Skills

- Good communication & presentational skills
- Creativity & Adaptability
- Decision Making & Problem Solving
- Curious and creative
- Highly motivated

Work Experience

4-Nov-2023 to Present *as Freelance SEO, Link Building Specialist, Content Writer*Job Responsibilities: -

- Working on projects- related to Digital Marketing, SEO, Web Design & Development, UI & UX Design, etc.
- Making Link building strategies such as- Resource Outreaching, Skyscraping, Guest Posting, Competitor's backlink analysis, Broken Link Building, Backlink Gap Analysis, Link Roundups, and Unlinked Brand Mentions etc.
- Finding Prospects via Manual Outreach for building data, Blogger/ Author/Admin outreach through social media groups, vendors etc.
- Backlink Building: Profile creation, forum posting, article/blog posting, pdf,ppt submission, blog commenting, social shares etc.
- Blog Optimization, Content optimization, Infographics creation, suggesting Blog topics

- to clients and Assigning content to the content team.
- Checking for proper anchor texts and LP placements in a content.
- Prepare weekly & monthly reports.
- SEO Tools- Ahrefs, SEMrush, Moz Link explorer, Google Analytics, Google Search Console etc.
- keyword research, content explorer
- Content Writing- Blog, Article and Social Media Posts
- Making creatives- Infographics, PPT, Invitation Cards, Pinterest, E-Invitation etc.

1-April-2023 to 29-September-2023 *Missive Digital as Sr. SEO Executive (Link Building Specialist)*

Job Responsibilities: -

- Link building- Skyscraping, Guest Posting, Competitor's backlink analysis, Broken Link Building, Backlink Gap Analysis, Link Roundups, Unlinked Brand Mentions etc.
- Working on projects- related to Digital Marketing, SEO, Web Design & Development, Web 3.0, UI & UX Design, HR Payroll Software, SAAS etc.
- Finding Prospects via Manual Outreach for collecting data, keyword research, content explorer, Blogger outreach, Author, through social media groups etc.
- Blog Optimization, Content optimization, Infographics creation, suggesting Blog topics to clients and Assigning content to the content team.
- Checking for proper anchor texts and LP placements in a content.
- Perform On-page activities- Title tags, Meta Description, anchor texts, image optimization, URL Optimization, whenever required for company's own website.
- Prepare weekly & monthly reports.
- SEO Tools- Ahrefs, SEMrush, Moz Link explorer, Hunter etc.

9-May- 2022 to 10-May- 2023 Techmagnate as SEO Analyst (Guest Posting)

Job Responsibilities: -

- Guest Posting via Manual Outreach collecting data, blogger outreach, Author, through social media groups etc.
- Link building Broken Link Building, Skyscraping link building
- Working for in house and few domestic client's project
- Content optimization, Assigning content to the content team.
- Checking for proper anchor texts and LP placements in a content.
- Perform On-page activity whenever required for company's own website.
- Keyword Research, Keyword Analysis, Competitor Analysis, etc.
- SEO Tools- Ahref, SEMrush, Moz Link Explorer, etc.

25-March-2021 to 24-March-2022 InVideo as SEO Consultant

Job Responsibilities: -

- Was working with Outreach Team for Building Links- Paid and Free Links
- Guest Posts via Manual Outreach, fetching & collecting data through tools, Blogger outreach, Author/ Admin outreach etc.
- Mass mail outreach- sending 50-100 mails in a day.
- Sharing blog ideas as per the site's niche to the client and assigning content to the content team
- Keyword Research, Keyword Analysis, Competitor Analysis, etc.
- SEO Tools- Ahref, Rebump, Hunter, Moz Link Explorer, Google Trends, etc.

09-May-2019 to 15-March-2021 *Cefnogi Solutions Pvt. Ltd. as SEO Executive*

Job Responsibilities: -

• Perform all off-page activities for company's own websites- provide tech support for hardware devices such as, Printer, CCTV, Router, Landlines etc.

- Projects Undertaken: gps-map-update.com, dialnfixit.com, camfixya.com, 247arlosupport.com, 247camerahelp.com
- Perform on-page tasks whenever required for company's own websites
- Off Page SEO- Blog Posting, Article Posting, web 2.0, Bookmarking, Classified, Forum Submission, Document Submission, Image Optimization, Image Creation, Video Creation etc.
- Keyword Analysis, Competitor Analysis
- SMO (on popular social networking sites)- feed posts once or twice a week
- Content Writing- Blog, Articles and Forums
- SEO Tools- Google Analytics, Google Webmaster, Google trends, Ubersuggest etc.

1-Nov-2017 to 31-Jan-2019 *Mify Solutions as Technical Support Executive (Email-Marketing)*

Job Responsibilities: -

- Solving all the queries of the clients related to panel and technical issues by chatand email support
- Email marketing of different services and the products as per client's requirement
- Maintain the IP and domain reputation reports on daily basis
- Provide demo- sessions also of the panel to the new clients
- Maintain all records like- Daily volume, performing campaigns of the clients etc.

Professional Qualification

MCA from IGNOU, 2017 BCA from IGNOU, 2014

Academic Qualification

Senior Secondary from CBSE Board with CS (Computer Science), 2009 Secondary from CBSE Board, 2007

Areas of Interest

Travelling & listening to Music, Learning new things, WatchingMovies, Cooking, Internet Surfing, etc.

Declaration

Place:

I hereby	declare	tnat	tne	above-fu	rnished	details	are	true	and	correct	to	tne	best	of	my
Knowled	lge and b	elief.													

Date:	(Signature